

MARCO ANTONIO SOSA

PHP | REACT FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Goal-oriented, Self-taught person. Used to working under pressure. 7+ years experience working abroad interpreting and implementing client requirements in a multicultural environment. I enjoy teamwork and I am eager to become a key participant of a bussines success, developing NodeJS Restful APIs, REST Web Services, React Frontend Applications, CRUD, CSS - HTML, with MySql and SQL Server databases. Immediate availability and willing to travel and relocate.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

BACKEND - FRONTEND DEVELOPMENT:

- PHP MySql Symfony
- NodelS REST API's
- React Functional Component
- React Hooks
- JSX code
- Material-UI Landing pages
- CSS Grid and Flexbox

COURSES:

- · JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures
- · APIs with Postman
- Modern React with Redux
- Microservices with Node JS and React
- PMP Certification Exam Preparation Seminar Feb 2014 - PMI - Arabian Gulf Chapter.
- · Arabic for Non-Native Speakers Nov 2013 - Qatar University.
- Website and Document Accesibility Workshop Nov 2011 - Qatar Assistive Technology Centre.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

JUN 2017 - JUN 2020

MediAccess S.A.P.I. de C.V. - Senior Web Programmer

Heavy development of SOL Server Stored Procedures. Shared administration of versioning. Frontend maintenance based on languages such as C#, PHP and few Java, React projects. APIs and Web Services with .Net, PHP and NodeJs.

CORE COMPETENCIES:

SQL Server (Stored Procedures, Transact-SQL), Codelgniter, Git versioning, Frontend with React, Angular, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, IOuerv.

JAN 2009 - AUG 2016 Qatar University, Doha, Qatar - Web Developer

Design and Developed the Official Website. Created and validated pages, apps and forms for all the University departments. Among the most relevant apps it was the Event Calendar, developed in pure PHP.

CORE COMPETENCIES:

PHP development with Dreamweaver and Symfony 3, MySql database, Git versioning, Frontend with Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery.

MAY 2006 - JUL 2008

Banco Nacional de México S.A. - Data Analyst

Data extraction with SQL. Presentation and analysis with MS Excel and VBA programming.

CORE COMPETENCIES:

Visual Basic for Applications, Microsoft Excel, Postgres Database.

JUN 2001 - APR 2006 RCI de México S.A. de C.V. - Web Developer

Collaboration in the design and deployment of the Corporative Intranet and the microsites for the company and associated resorts. Database was primarily SQL Server although PostgreSQL was often used.

CORE COMPETENCIES:

JSP's (Java), PHP, Perl, ASP's, SQL Server, Dreamweaver, Photoshop.

EDUCATION



Administrative Computer Science UNIVERSIDAD TECNOLÓGICA DE MÉXICO

CALL ME MAYBE

+52 55 3070 2528 WEBSITE: www.marcososa.me **EMAIL:** marcososarosales@gmail.com 9-Jul-1971 D.O.B.: LOCATION: Mexico City

AROUT

Mobile First fan. I have found a new passion in Frontend development. The thrill of problem-solving through Single Page Apps with the tools available nowadays it seems to me nothing less than artisan work.

LANGUAGES

Spanish Native

English Proficient in both

speaking and writing

SKILLS

JAVASCRIPT **** **★★★☆☆** REACT ***** **ANGULAR** **** PHP **** OOP *** CODEIGNITER SOL SERVER **** **** MYSQL **** CSS **** MATERIAL-UI

SOCIAL MEDIA



marco antonio sosa rosales



marco_sosa_rosales



masosar



@marksosar